healthdirect.gov.au 2019-12-09

# Privacy policy | healthdirect

## Important privacy information

This document describes how Healthdirect Australia Ltd (Healthdirect Australia) and its contractors collect, use, disclose and store your personal information.

We may collect your name, address, date of birth, information about your illnesses, symptoms, disabilities and information required to provide you with a health service.

We usually collect personal information directly from you when you use our interactive services (for example, via telephone or video call), when you use our online services (for example, our websites), send us written correspondence or complete an online form.

We sometimes collect information from a third party, for example from a healthcare service such as a residential care facility who is managing your care or from your family members. Also, if someone calls on behalf of another person, we collect the caller’s name and contact details.

We collect, use and disclose your personal information for the purpose of providing our services, conducting our business, communicating with you, assisting your Commonwealth, State or Territory health services or department of health to provide you with health services or to address issues you may raise with them, matching service delivery data with health information for service improvement, the compilation and analysis of statistics relevant to public health and safety and complying with our legal obligations.

If you choose not to provide your personal information to Healthdirect Australia this may affect your ability to take full advantage of the services offered (for instance, our online video call service).

Healthdirect Australia will also share relevant information with contractors that perform its services or dispose of its documents, other health service providers, health services and/or Government bodies in the event of a national or jurisdictional health disaster in order that an appropriate health response can be provided. We don’t disclose your information to anyone outside Australia.

If you would like further information, please view our Privacy Statement at www.healthdirect.gov.au/privacy-statement for information about:

  * how you may access and request correction of your personal information that is held by Healthdirect Australia; and
  * how to make a complaint about the handling of your personal information and how your complaint will be dealt with by Healthdirect Australia.

## Contact details

Contact our Privacy Officer about privacy-related matters:

**Email:** [privacy@healthdirect.org.au](mailto:privacy@healthdirect.org.au)  
**Phone:** (02) 9263 9000  
**Facsimile:** (02) 9283 9180

**Postal address:**  
Privacy Officer  
Healthdirect Australia  
PO Box K411  
Haymarket NSW 1240
